Today
A part of me
And I cannot
Mourn.
Because they forget
All the synonyms
Of "sadness".
Now
All that I can do
Without you
Is replace you.
The hell with this.
Hello?
Is there anyone here?
God...
Son of a bitch.
Tom at the Farm
Sir, what are you doing in my house?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I only had his address, so...
Tom. I'm Tom.
Sorry for the mess. It's been hell.
- It's okay.
- It was so fast.
I couldn't find a hotel...
Hotels are not our specialty.
You can have a nice black couch.
Thank you.
Ma'am...
I should have started well. Forget it.
My condolences.
You can call me Agatha.
No friends called. I
guess he had no friends.
He seemed like a smart
kid. I bet he envied them.
Don't tell me you're leaving tomorrow.
He always said that.
With whom would you stay.
And you'll say something at the funeral?
Yes, I wrote some words.
But it's something casual, humble.
He speaks well. If you speak, they
will know my son was a good boy.
You can sleep in his bed.
It's clean. I wash
the sheets every month.
I don't know why, but I do.
Tom, with a trout reached, no?
- Yes.
- I catch his brother's.
- Who?
- His brother.
I'm full of fish.
You might find butter in
the refrigerator below?
Yeah, right.
You look like him. Your eyes.
It's funny. Well, it's not funny, but...
I didn't know he had a brother.
It's true. Francis.
He handles the farm
since my husband died.
Then...
What do you do?
I'm an editor at an advertising agency.
We worked together.
We were co-workers.
Friends, colleagues...
When I saw you, yelling.
- I should have said...
- I'm sorry.
If a woman finds a
stranger in the house...
The only person who should
have been there was not.
That people do now? This fashion?
Who is this person?
Not important.
You're using his settlement, no?
Smells good.
I knew you would come.
I knew.
I don't know you, but I knew.
Shut up. Don't say
anything to my mother.
She's already quite sad. She
doesn't need to know anything more.
You're not important to us.
Tomorrow at the church,
You'll say some nice words.
And Agatha will love it.
And everyone will love it.
It'll be great.
Then, you'll pack your things.
You'll be out of our lives.
You'll be gone.
Did you sleep well last night?
Yes, and you?
I don't sleep much. I read.
I love what you wrote, Tom.
Sounds very nice, Agathe.
People cry a lot.
And I brought a CD with a
song I'd like to add later.
- Good.
- A song he liked.
If that's no problem.
Of course. It's fine.
Go fix instead of strut.
And no fragrance, by the way.
I smell you. Perfume is for
weddings, not for funerals.
Agreed?
Our young friend.
Was good with his
hands, you have told me.
He liked to paint,
He danced, and sure was good at it.
Now, our friend,
Our son, our confidant,
Our brother,
Do paintings for Christ,
Since God is infinite
And loves pretty things.
We might think: "He's gone.
We leave.
It is unfair. "
But another voice will
say: "No, no it isn't.
He came home.
And along with Christ,
he has done justice.
Joining our loved ones who have died.
Together they will laugh, sing
and eat whatever they want. "
Now listen to a friend of Guy's.
Guillaume!
Guillaume, excuse me.
A friend of Guillaume's
will speak about him.
- I'm sorry.
- It's fine.
Not if...
So, we will hear a song.
You're asking for trouble.
Fuck, you scared me.
Your speech in the church?
At the end there was no speech.
Yeah, I know...
What are you doing?
Don't touch me, okay?
What happened to the speech?
My mother was very sad.
I can not see it well.
I can't.
I told you what you had to do.
It was pretty simple.
Very simple, no?
Enough!
"We're going on holiday
in Ajaccio today. "
"Who is this?"
We talked on the phone a year ago.
I remember your voice.
When I heard, I knew you would come.
That would ruin everything.
Now back to the house.
I hope you make up for it.
To talk about Sarah.
Well, my mother is.
Sarah is a compulsive smoker.
She loves pasta.
Don't worry, you will do it.
That's it.
I thought you wanted
me out of your life.
Fuck you.
"Accomplish. " "Make it clear. "
Accomplish this, motherfucker. Whore.
You're on your own, farmer.
Fuck my luggage.
Sit down, Agathe.
I noticed you were uncomfortable, Tom.
The trout circled inside
his stomach all night.
I would love to hear your speech.
Sorry. The thing is...
It was poorly done and
I had not rehearsed.
I'm sure it was touching.
Whore.
That bitch should have been there.
Tom talked to her.
Who is "her"?
Her, Sarah.
- Yes, I talked from the car.
- They talked from the car.
- What did you say?
- Tell him.
You can shut up?
She said:
"Today a part of me has died.
There are no words to describe
the void that must be filled. "
Then he said:
"You are despicable. You are nothing.
You're useless on Earth
And if you could not stop his death,
It is a waste of time to cry. "
I said
They want to know.
But, for him, the love
was between two people.
No friends, no family,
no intruders, no...
She said that he was
her first true love.
Then I hung up.
And then he said:
"I hate myself. "
"I will do my best to
leave everything clear. "
Then I hung up.
She should have come.
To say all that to me.
Francis.
Give Tom clothes and show your brother.
What?
How to milk the cows.
You were awesome.
You forced me to lie.
No. I meant the cows.
You are kind to animals.
The caress.
Never thought that machines
were as technological milking.
Yes. Now there's a laser.
It would be much less work.
Who was the boy you
wouldn't let in the church?
Why does nobody talk to you?
In the center. I mean,
it was your brother.
I'm not important to people, so...
People do not care, you know?
You were right there.
I love animals, so... I think...
No, I mean Sarah. The
conversation on the telephone.
I told my brother: "Do not tell Mom,
But give me a picture with a
girl. Whenever pretty, you know?
So it was that Sarah was born.
- Work companions, it seems.
- Sarah Thibault?
Sarah. Sarah Thibault, the
girl at the photocopier.
Here she is.
You carry it in your
wallet like a trophy?
Why not?
It's the only picture of him I have.
Namely, recent.
My mom likes it. I was
very proud when she saw it.
Would you lie to your
mother if you wanted to?
Not the world you live
in, you do, what you want,
But I think I already
did everything I could do.
I would tell your mother
everything and then I'll be gone.
You're choking me! You're choking me!
Do not tell me what to do or
how to love my mother, all right?
Once you're here, you're here.
Now you follow the current.
Are you okay?
Then dip in chlorine
every day for a week.
No more than two teaspoons each pint.
Then, the ointment and Cloxacillin.
The pharmacist will explain.
What relationship do
you have with Longchamp?
Really? Longchamp is Podowski?
Distant relatives.
They are distant relatives.
I came for the funeral.
How well do you know your relatives?
Each day a little more.
Well, all right.
Have a good trip to
Montreal, Mr. Podowski.
Tom, you have something here.
I fell.
This morning, when I
opened the door of your room
I saw two precious children asleep.
Two young children.
You're content, no?
What happened? Did you damage?
- I went to the doctor.
- The doctor? For what?
Damage was placed on the conveyor belt.
Help him cut the meat.
Tell me more about her.
Did she say something else?
She said to tell you he had strong arms.
She loved when you get
up and back into sound.
"I loved feeling his sweaty
armpits on my shoulders. "
"Sometimes, as I was walking, I
knew the sex would be incredible.
"Take off your shirt. "
"Show me your armpits.
Put them on my lips. "
"Get your dick through the
fly and squirt in my face. "
Well...
Sarah is a bitch, no?
A bitch!
Tom, pretty bitch, no?
Fucking bitch!
The queen of all whores!
It feels good to laugh.
You're good with her.
She hasn't laughed like
that in a long time.
You told the doctor?
- That I did this to you...
- No.
I should have taken you to other people.
For what?
You never asked why I've lived
with my mother for 30 years?
I can make a woman happy.
I have a beautiful farm.
I am looking.
I know you like me.
Do not go.
I said you'd get dirty.
If it bleeds!
Are you okay?
Let me help you.
I'm sorry.
I'm fine. I've never seen a calf born.
I grabbed it by surprise.
It's called a Rear Bitch.
Because you have a rear fucking.
I shake it.
- What?
- Shake it.
Next time you go on a whim...
Try to go for the soybean field.
It's October, corn cuts like a knife.
- I don't do that.
- Do it.
No, I can't. I have tachycardia.
I used to take tango
lessons with my brother.
It was his idea. I wanted to socialize.
All the girls wanted handsome farmers.
We were.
This girl...
One of the classes, it was...
It was the maximum.
The girl at the store
said it was silk velvet.
He said that this would suffice.
What would you not give him?
Who taught you?
Not bad.
I'm stuck here for my mother.
I could go, but I can't.
I can't leave her alone.
I'll have to take it
one day at a residence.
The five years of total madness.
I got tired of looking
like growing corn.
Milk cows, scare coyotes. It's boring.
Some want to leave fast.
Find her one morning
on the kitchen floor.
With the phone in hand, drooling soil,
With blank eyes.
It would be sad, because I love her.
But she did not want
to go to a nursing home.
Sell...
I made an apple pie.
She had a nice calf.
We'll call it Rear Bitch.
That's not a name for a calf.
What do you want to call her?
Yes. Every word.
And I said that's not a name for a calf.
Come and eat the cake before it cools.
It's your fault.
Go change. We'll go for a walk.
What are we doing?
To buy beer. We'll get drunk somewhere.
I thought I'd take you to a bar. Let
me teach you the place, or something.
You're a waste of sperm.
What is the reason for your life?
You smell bad.
Did you put on perfume?
A little bit.
Perfume is for weddings.
That's it?
Stronger.
Tell me when to stop.
You're the boss.
You smell like him.
And you have the same voice.
The same fucking voice.
I'll wait in the truck.
I'm Tom. Sorry to call so late.
I could not sleep.
Listen...
Can you come over?
It's here.
- You can not drive me home?
- No.
Why not? It's close.
Do not enter that house.
Fifty dollars please.
Thank you very much. Good night.
Sorry about the mess. It has been hell.
But if I'd known you were
coming, I would have made pasta.
My son Francis and Guillaume
told me that you love pasta.
But not today.
It's very sweet of
you, but I'm satisfied.
You're beautiful, young lady.
Strange to say now that is gone.
Francis, this is
Sarah. The lovely Sarah.
What the fuck is this?
Come on! It is your
brother's girlfriend.
How silly I am.
Francis smokes these
on special occasions.
He'll share, no?
You can smoke in here.
My husband did from 1971 to 2001, so...
I don't smoke, ma'am.
My brother knows how to pick them.
Francis, go find Tom.
Then give him some tea.
Tom is feeding the cows.
- Thank you.
- You're more attractive in person.
It's a nice house.
It's very cozy...
You do not do that here,
but my mother is happy.
Make sure it stays that way.
Damn, you're sexy.
You're totally crazy.
What are you doing here?
Tom said your mom would
be happy if I were here
and said I was the
girlfriend of Guillaume.
He did not say that I smoked.
And you love pasta.
- How many languages do you speak?
- Four.
Shit.
Fuck you.
Fuck you until you bleed.
How much do you owe?
Pretty sure you need to
come to brighten a stranger.
Come look.
Come, come, come.
I did not want to ruin the surprise!
I'm so glad you're here.
It means a lot to me.
We're glad you came.
Let her try.
- This is...
- Test.
Let's go to the living room.
I will make pasta then.
By far we did not have much company.
Since my husband died.
Come on, don't be shy.
- Sit next to me, Sarah.
- All right.
I don't know if pasta is a good idea.
I don't think Sarah is staying...
Why not? Spend the night here!
I'll miss my bus.
You'll stay today and
tomorrow you'll take a bus.
It's sad you could not
come to the funeral.
I had no strength...
- Agathe
- Agathe, I know.
We'll drink something, at least.
We'll drink something in his memory.
I have a good brandy in my room.
Francis, bring good
glasses from the garage.
We dress well. We're not savages.
I'm going to smoke.
Yes, yes. I smoke.
I do not know why I lied. I'm a fool.
We are going to smoke, Tom.
These people work all the time.
You have to see my calf. I have a calf.
She's called Rear Bitch. The
brainchild of Frank, of course.
In my honor, apparently.
A 45 minute delivery, was
born with a twisted paw.
- The vet had to come...
- Go get your stuff.
We'll take your car.
You don't want to go home?
Heavens. That idiot attacked
me. I didn't understand at first,
But thank God you called.
Shit, now I understand.
Look, I don't know if he told you,
but I apologize on their behalf.
He's fine. He won't change.
Apology.
Hey, Tom.
This is all bruised. You
all have a black neck.
You will have to sell me on going.
You have no idea the work
that goes into 48 cows.
It's a great job.
At some point, his mother interned.
He was alone here.
Meanwhile, I'm no good
at all. I'm worthless.
What will I do?
Buy a laser machine to milk.
He has a common machine.
I'll buy the laser.
It will be incredible.
They're like a family, Sarah.
They did not know three weeks ago.
I can not explain it.
Look, this place...
It's real. Everything is so real...
A cow gives birth, there's
blood. A dog barks, you hear.
Hey, calm down. Calm down.
I did come for the
girlfriend of a dead man.
You want to talk about real things?
Your boyfriend lied to his mother.
You think he didn't lie to you too?
I slept with him.
Okay?
I'm telling you now,
but it's nothing new.
Everyone slept with him, Tom.
You had on your bike or in
your car. That was the signal.
In some alley. Short but good.
You know what?
Get your stuff.
And we'll talk in the car.
How often?
How often have you slept?
Find your fucking bag!
They ended up smoking? Come on!
I have no car.
- We'll take her.
- What?
- We'll take her to the station.
- Just arrived.
Listen.
The last bus is at midnight.
Tom, do what you want.
- What did you say? We're fine.
- Nothing.
Don't touch it.
No need to say anything, I can see it.
You will go to the cemetery with my mother
to visit the grave of your boyfriend.
I'll say that you want to see his grave.
Then you take the bus.
In fact, I'll decide.
I'm not scared of you.
We'll take a walk through the corn.
The corn cuts like a knife.
What is this?
His first report card.
His first watch.
Whoever bought it in St. Anne.
These are his notebooks
where he drew, wrote...
How do you have them?
Not the ride?
He left them here.
In my room.
- His reading?
- No.
But now, if you can
help me understand...
Would you open one?
We would read? Sarah is here.
You were close to him.
That's boring. We have company.
It's a bad idea.
It's a bad idea, Tom?
His tie of Confirmation.
A lock of hair.
He was 16 years old when he left.
I had that hair...
So pretty.
Really nice.
Then return and had very short.
It's for you, Sarah.
It's all yours now, yes?
Why not take the box?
Why not do what it should do?
Why not this sad?
Why not run to his grave?
- She wants...
- Why not bring me flowers?
Why didn't Tom speak in the church?
Why I let my son visit me?
Because he said he'd call and write?
What kind of accident was it?
With whom was he?
How was it? Where? When?
Nobody dies at 25!
- Nobody, nobody, nobody...!
- Shut up!
I'll take you to the station.
I'm drunk.
Come on...
- Here you go.
- Fucking psychopaths.
Damn bunch of fucking psychos.
So God made?me.
A gift for you.
God.
What the hell...?
Fuck, what will I do with this?
I don't know, use it.
It's very soft.
Do you want to go for a walk?
Go for a walk.
Me?
You and your friends in the back seat.
AUTHENTIC
What do you want, Blondie?
Barrel or bottle?
A pint of lager.
On the way.
Three dollars, please.
Keep the change, sir.
Where is that accent from?
It's from there.
What brings you here?
My man died.
I came to the funeral and
helped in the Longchamp farm.
I hope you came alone.
- Yeah.
- Because the big guy is not welcome.
You are prohibited from coming.
Are you all right, ladies?
Why?
Why what?
Why am I prohibited from coming here?
You know why.
No, I'm not from here.
It's not fun.
Tell me.
Look, son, if you stay in that house,
I respect that. I do not
want to talk about it.
I give a shit.
I want to know.
It was here, nine years ago.
I remember because Josee and I
We were celebrating the
thirtieth anniversary of the bar.
Everyone was having a good
time, singing and dancing,
We were drunk.
Francis was here with his brother.
Strutting on the runway.
Turning and gliding like professionals.
Presumably.
Impressing the girls.
Anyway...
Then, the boy, his brother Francis...
- Guillaume.
- Guillaume, dammit.
He started dancing with a guy,
a friend, someone your age.
A guy with white jeans
and a green shirt.
Francis came and asked for a beer.
The guy who danced with his brother
I went over to talk with him...
He sat there, two seats.
I said something, and the scandal began.
That's it.
What did you say?
You remember the green
shirt and white jeans.
Don't push your luck.
I said:
"I have to tell you something
about your brother. Take a seat. "
Francis then fell on him.
He grabbed his face with
both hands and opened it.
- It opened?
- Here...
Deep throat.
From the ear to the throat.
- And then?
- You haven't had enough?
Yeah, but...
- The boy?
- The boy, the boy...
I never saw it.
Some say he lives in a village west.
Others saw it and were sure it was him.
I don't know, because you work all day.
The last time I went
there was to use the phone.
During a storm in 1997.
That's it.
That's why Francis is
prohibited from entering.
Okay?
Thank you.
Where are you?
I'm sorry!
Don't go!
I won't hurt you, Tom.
What will happen to me?
Tom, don't do this!
I need you! I need you here!
I'm very disappointed, Tom!
I would never do
something like that! Never!
I try to be a better person!
Shit, Tom!
Son of a bitch!
Wait until you find...
I hear you.
Fuck!
Need anything else?
No, thank you. Tank 1, please.
- Thank you, sir.
- Thank you, goodbye.